Leo A. Lerner Papers
Leo A. Lerner Papers
- General Subject File
  - North Town Chamber of Commerce (Box 42)
  - Northernaire (Box 42)
  - Northwest Realty Corporation (Jackson, Arthur) (Box 42)
  - Northwestern University (Box 42)
  - O, miscellaneous, 1943-1963 (Box 42)
  - Offset file (Box 42)
  - Open Court Publishing Co. (Box 42)
  - Orient trip, 1963 (Box 42)
  - O'Rourke, Robert J., Alderman, 48th (Box 43)
  - P, miscellaneous, 1943-1957; 2 folders (Box 43)
  - Peoples Gas, Light & Coke Co. (Box 43)
  - Peltz, Cissie Libshutz (Box 43)
  - J.R. Pershall Co. (Box 43)
  - Petrie, Donald A. (Box 43)
  - Photographic costs (Box 43)
  - Petroleum Heat and Power Co. (Box 43)
  - Pica's Peek (Box 43)
  - Pillen, Herbert C. (Box 43)
  - Pioneer Publishing Co. (Box 43)
  - Politics, 2 folders (Box 44)
  - Pollak, Robert (Box 44)
  - Portes, Caesar (Box 44)
  - Price Paper Corp. (Wickliffe B. Moore) (Box 44)
  - Print Promotion (Box 44)
  - Printing Center (Wm. McDonnell) (Box 44)
  - Printing correspondence. (Box 44)
  - Prospective customers for printing jobs (Box 44)
  - Publicity Club of Chicago (Box 44)
  - Publishers Auxiliary (Box 44)
  - Publishers' statements
  - Pulitzer Prize (Hillman Foundation) (Box 44)
  - Pucinski, Roman C., Congressman (Box 44)
  - Q, miscellaneous, 1943-1962 (Box 44)
  - Quaal, Ward L. (Box 44)
  - Quilici, George L. (Box 44)
  - Quinn, James R. (Box 44)
  - R, miscellaneous, 1943-1965; 4 folders (Box 45)
  - Race discrimination (Box 45)
  - Rapid Reading Program (Box 46)
  - Ravenswood Hospital (Box 46)
  - Receipts, Civic Organizations, etc. (Box 46)
  - Red Owl Stores (Box 46)
  - Reitzel, Al (Box 46)
  - Remington Typewriter Co. (Box 46)
  - Republican National Committee (Conventions) (Box 46)
  - Resa, Alexander (Box 46)
  - Robie House (Box 46)
  - Roosevelt University
    - Miscellaneous, 1950-1956; 3 folders (Box 46)
    - Miscellaneous, 1956-1958; 4 folders (Box 47)
    - Miscellaneous, 1958-1965; 4 folders (Box 48)
    - Reports (Box 48)
    - Board of Trustees Minutes (Box 49)
    - By-Laws, amendments, constitution (Box 49)
    - Faculty Manual, 1948-1949 (Box 49)
    - Journalism 201, papers (Box 49)
    - Report of the President, 1950-1951 (Box 49)
    - Treasurer's Reports (Box 49)
    - Auditorium restoration (Sparling) (Box 50)
    - Auditorium restoration (Box 50)
    - Auditorium restoration (incl. Lerner's resignation) (Box 50)
  - Rose Bowl game (Box 50)
  - Rosenberg, Marvin (Box 50)
  - Rosenberg, Thomas (Box 50)
  - Rosenblatt, Abner (Box 50)
  - Rosenbloom, I. J. (Box 50)
  - Rotman, Morris (Box 51)
  - Rover, Edmund (Box 51)
  - S, miscellaneous
    - 1943-1955, 4 folders (Box 51)
    - 1956-1958 (Box 52)
    - 1960-1965 (Box 53)
  - Sachs, Morris B. (Box 53)
  - Sain, Frank G., sheriff (Box 53)
  - St. Lawrence Project (Box 53)
  - Salomon, Kurt J. (Box 53)
  - Saltiel, Ed (Box 53)
  - Sandburg, Carl (Box 53)
  - Sane nuclear policy (Box 53)
  - Saperstein, Esther (Box 53)
  - Satin, Max (Box 53)
  - Scandinavian Seminar, 2 folders (Box 54)
  - Schooler, Lee (Public Relations Board) (Box 54)
  - Schrayer, Max (Associated Agencies) (Box 54)
  - Schwartz, Nate (Box 54)
  - Sears, Roebuck and Co. (Box 55)
  - Semrow Broadcasting Co., Inc. (WNMP) (Box 55)
  - Semrow, Harry (Box 55)
  - The Sentinel (Box 55)
  - Shapiro, Samuel H. (Box 55)
  - Sherman Hotel (Box 55)
  - Shimer College (Box 55)
  - Showell, John (Box 55)
  - Shriver, Sargent (Box 55)
  - Shumate, Al (Accredited Newspaper Association) (Box 55)
  - Simon, Seymour (Box 55)
  - Social Security Administration (Box 55)
  - Solon, Joseph (Box 55)
  - South End Reporter (Raymond Kelly) (Box 55)
  - South Town Economist (Box 55)
  - Southern Illinois University (Box 55)
  - Sperling, Jack (Box 55)
  - Staff (Box 55)
  - Staff memos, 2 folders (Box 56)
  - Stamp plan (Box 56)
  - Statement of ownership (Box 56)
  - Stevenson for President
    - Miscellaneous (Box 56)
    - Miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 57)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 58)
  - Starr case (Box 58)
  - Stratton, William G., Governor (Box 58)
  - Stone, Jerome H. (Box 58)
  - Suburbia (Box 58)
  - Sun Press, Cleveland (Harry Volk) (Box 58)
  - Sun Times-reprints of L. A. L. editorials (Box 58)
  - Sur-Prize-O (Box 59)
  - Surveys, Lerner area (Box 59)
  - Sweeney, Frank (Box 59)
  - Swim carnival (Box 59)
  - Swinarski, Theodore A. (Box 59)
  - Synagogues, Sisterhoods, Men's Clubs, etc. (Box 59)
  - T, misc. (Box 59)
  - Taylor, Crombie (Box 59)
  - Taxes, miscellaneous (Box 59)
  - Television broadcasting and radio stations (Box 59)
  - Theta Sigma Phi (Box 59)
  - Thillers, Mel (Box 59)
  - Time Magazine (Box 59)
  - Times Home Newspapers (Box 59)
  - U, miscellaneous (Box 60)
  - Unger, Martin E. (Box 60)
  - Unions (Box 60)
  - United Nations (Box 60)
    See also Lerner, Deana.
  - United Nations, San Francisco Conference (Box 60)
  - U.S. Congressmen, Senators and miscellaneous (Box 60)
  - U.S. Department of Commerce Community Relations Service (Box 60)
  - U.S. Department of Interior (Box 60)
  - U.S. Department of Labor (Box 60)
  - U.S. Post Office Department (Box 60)
  - U.S. Treasury Department (Box 60)
  - United Steelworkers of America (Box 61)
  - Universal Pictures (Ben Katz) (Box 61)
  - University of Chicago (Box 61)
  - University of Illinois (Box 61)
  - Universities, colleges and schools (Box 61)
  - Uptown Commission (Box 61)
  - Uptown Federal Savings and Loan Association (Box 61)
  - Uptown National Bank of Chicago (Box 61)
  - V, miscellaneous (Box 61)
  - W, miscellaneous, 1951-1965; 3 folders (Box 61)
  - WMAQ (Box 62)
  - Walgreen Drug Stores (Box 62)
  - Walker, Claude (Box 62)
  - Weber, Alban (Box 62)
  - Weber, Charles (Box 62)
  - Weintraub, Ben (Box 62)
  - Weiss, Edward W. (Box 62)
  - Western Union (Box 62)
  - Westinghouse Broadcasting Co. (Box 62)
  - Wheels, Inc. (Box 62)
  - White House (Box 62)
  - Whitman, Walt (Box 62)
  - Wieboldt Stores, Inc. (Box 62)
  - Wieboldt's Dept. Store (Box 62)
  - Wigoda, Paul T. (Box 62)
  - Will, Herbert L. (Box 62)
  - Willens, Sherwin (Box 62)
  - Winsberg's Dept. Store (Box 62)
  - X, Y, Z, miscellaneous (Box 62)
  - Yates, Sidney R., Congressman (Box 62)
  - Yates for U. S. Senator (Box 63)
  - Young Men's Christian Association, 3 folders (Box 63)
  - Zelezinski, A. V. and Swinarski, T. A. (Box 63)
- Personal File
  - Correspondence
    - 1931-1946, 5 folders (Box 64)
    - 1947-1950, 4 folders (Box 65)
    - 1951-1954, 4 folders (Box 66)
    - 1955-1958, 4 folders (Box 67)
    - 1959-1962, 4 folders (Box 68)
    - 1964-1965 (Box 69)
    - Misc. unidentified correspondence, 1929; undated (Box 69)
  - Subject File
    - Continental Journey, materials concerning European tour, 1960 (Box 70)
    - Farm mortgage
      - 1947-1955, 2 folders (Box 70)
      - 1956-1965, 2 folders (Box 71)
      - Addition & Furniture (Box 71)
    - Hawaiian trip, 1964 (Box 71)
    - Herrick Award (Box 71)
    - Home, 4300 Marine Drive (Box 71)
    - House, 2120 W. Lunt, sale of, 1959 (Box 71)
    - The Italics Are Mine, materials concerning (Box 71)
    - The Itch Of Opinion, materials concerning (Box 72)
    - Jaguar [automobile - "Jagulars are such very good droppers!"] (Box 72)
    - Lerner, Deana, letters from L.A.L. (Box 72)
    - Miscellaneous unidentified papers and notes (Box 72)
    - Photographs of people (Box 72)
    - Photographs of papers (Box 72)
    - Silver jubilee, 1951 (Box 72)
  - Journals
    - Personal notebook, undated (Box 73)
    - Pocket calendars, 1944-1964 (Box 73)
- Manuscripts
  - Speeches, etc.
    - 1941-1946, 5 folders (Box 74)
    - 1947-1954, 7 folders (Box 75)
    - 1955-1959, 5 folders (Box 76)
    - 1960-1962 (Box 77)
    - Miscellaneous speech, article, & editorial materials (Box 77)
- Published Materials
  - Articles by Lerner, 1931-1966; undated (Box 78)
  - Articles about Lerner, 1936-1965 (Box 78)
  - Miscellaneous, 1939-1966; undated (Box 79)
- Tape Recordings
  - Recordings of broadcasts (Box 80)
- Correspondence (1979 addition)
  - Business, 1935-1966 (Box 1)
  - Congratulatory, 1946-1964 (Box 1)
  - Personal, 1927-1968 (Box 1)
- Memorabilia (1979 addition)
  - Awards and memorial photographs (Box 1)
- Printed material (1979 addition)
  - General, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - General (Box 2)
- Writings (1979 addition)
  - Books
    - Continental Journey (Box 2)
    - The Italics are Mine (Box 2)
    - The Itch of Opinion (Box 2)
    - Truth Ripens, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Reviews of Lerner's books (Box 2)
  - Editorials, 1936-1953; 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Editorials, 1954-1965; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Typescripts and holographs (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Tape recordings (Box 3)